# **David Garner**

# Software Developer

### <u>dprgarner@gmail.com</u> · <u>Github</u> · <u>LinkedIn</u>

I'm a full-stack web developer and technical team lead based in London. My primary focus is front-end development with React, but I also have considerable professional experience in back-end development with Django, Python, and Node.js. I place a strong emphasis on quality in all of my code, and consider unit testing and code review to be essential parts of the development process.

# Skills

- Front-end: React, Redux, RxJS, TypeScript, SCSS, Webpack, jQuery, Recent ECMAScript Features, Responsive Design
- Back-end: Python, Node.js, Django, Docker, Express, Solr, ElasticSearch
- AWS: CloudFormation, CloudWatch, Fargate, CloudFront, Lambda
- Testing: Mocha, Jest, Selenium, TDD, BDD, pytest
- Source Control and CI/CD: Git, Jenkins, TeamCity, Gitlab CI, Subversion
- Command line tools: Vim, Bash, common Unix tools (grep, sed, make, etc.)
- Process Management: Jira, Trello, Scrum, Kanban

# **Employment History**

### 2020–present: Senior Frontend Lead, then Technical Lead at QMetric, London, UK

- Took ownership of the JavaScript codebase within a home insurance platform, built with Domain Driven Design in a cloud-native, event-driven, microservice architecture
- Designed and prototyped a Microfrontend architecture to support parallel teams developing the same web app
- Collaborated with the infrastructure team to containerise the legacy JavaScript services to run in AWS Fargate
- Set and assessed technical tests and interviewed candidate frontend developers

#### 2019–20: Engineering Lead at Mintel, London, UK

#### Technical Team Lead for a Search App

- Architected the front-end build for a revamped single-page search app
- Collaborated with Product Development and Project Leads to ensure the technical requirements for requested features were considered, planned-out, and communicated with developers in London, Chicago, and Shanghai
- Held responsibility for technical direction, tech-debt prioritisation, and code quality standards on the project

#### Code Owner for Internal Front-End Libraries

- Helped implement the company's design system using internal React libraries
- Designed and reviewed component APIs, emphasising backwards-compatibility and extensibility
- Ran a half-day introductory workshop on React and working on our internal UI Components library

#### 2015–19: Software Developer at Mintel, London, UK

Gained a wide range of experience with legacy and new codebases, primarily with React frontends and Django back-ends, specialising in front-end development

#### Apps, Projects, and Tools

- Built a dashboard app for displaying and collating direct marketing data with a team based in Chicago
- Prototyped and created an app for dynamically collating and crossing consumer survey data in tables and charts
- Created internal tools and libraries to help with visual regressions testing and browserbased Selenium testing

#### Other

- Joined remote and in-person interview panels for potential interns, graduate developers, and senior front-end developers
- Gave talks on Visual Regressions testing, TypeScript, Styled Components, and design patterns in React
- Helped found the "Front-End Chapter", a cross US-UK team group dedicated to sharing knowledge and best practices in front-end development
- Organised and participated in cross-company coding competitions on competitive gameplaying Als and image classification challenges
- Ran a lunchtime "Coding Club" teaching front-end frameworks and TDD

# Education

# 2011–15: Queen Mary University of London, London, UK

Degree: Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Theoretical Physics (String Theory)

• Published <u>peer-reviewed papers</u>, gave talks at multiple academic institutions, taught Physics undergraduates

### 2007–11: University of Cambridge (Christ's College), Cambridge, UK

Degree: BA with MMath, Mathematical Tripos, First Class/Honours Pass

#### Interests

## Coding

- Contributed to various open source JavaScript projects
- Attended conferences and meetups on TypeScript, React, and GraphQL
- Experimented in personal projects with GraphQL, Apollo, NumPy, TensorFlow, Haskell

#### Other

Board games, metal, folk, sci-fi, running, swimming, craft beer

View online